would you call me crazy?
فهل ستقولون أنني مجنون؟
I wouldn't blame you,
لن ألومكم إذًا،
because every time I look at this Arctic selfie, I shiver just a little bit.
في كل مرة أنظر إلى هذه الصورة الذاتية، أرتجف قليلاً.
I want to tell you a little bit about this photograph.
أريد أن أخبركم بعض التفاصيل عن هذه الصورة.
I was swimming around in the Lofoten Islands in Norway,
كنت أسبح في جزر لوفوتين في النرويج،
just inside the Arctic Circle,
داخل منطقة القطب الشمالي،
and the water was hovering right at freezing.
وكان الماء على وشك أن يتجمد.
The air? A brisk -10 with windchill,
أما الهواء؟ فرياح باردة بدرجة حرارة 10 تحت الصفر،
and I could literally feel the blood trying to leave my hands,
وكنت بالفعل أشعر وكأن الدم ينسحب من يدي،
feet and face, and rush to protect my vital organs.
وقدمي ووجهي ويتدفق لحماية أعضائي الحيوية.
It was the coldest I've ever been.
كان هذا أبرد جو تعرضت له.
But even with swollen lips, sunken eyes, and cheeks flushed red,
ولكن حتى مع شفاه متورمة وعينين غائرتين ووجنتين مضرجتين بالحمرة،
I have found that this place right here is somewhere I can find great joy.
وجدت أن هذا المكان هنا يعج بالكثير من المتعة.
Now, when it comes to pain, psychologist Brock Bastian
والآن، بالنسبة للشعور بالألم، فإن عالم النفس "بروك باستشن"
probably said it best when he wrote,
عبّر عن الأمر بشكل أفضل عندما كتب:
"Pain is a kind of shortcut to mindfulness.
"الألم طريق مختصر إلى اليقظة.
It makes us suddenly aware of everything in the environment.
لأنه يجعلك تشعر فجأة بكل شيء في البيئة.
It brutally draws us in
فهو يسحبنا بشدة
to a virtual sensory awareness of the world much like meditation."
إلى وعي حسي افتراضي بالعالم مثلما يحدث في التأمل."
If shivering is a form of meditation, then I would consider myself a monk.
وإذا كان الارتجاف أحد أنماط التأمل، فإنني قد أعتبر نفسي راهبًا إذًا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, before we get into the why
والآن قبل أن نستعرض لماذا
would anyone ever want to surf in freezing cold water?
يريد أي شخص أن يتزلج على ماء بارد متجمد؟
I would love to give you a little perspective
فإنني أود أن أقدم لكم فكرة بسيطة عن وجهة نظري
on what a day in my life can look like.
حول كيف يبدو أي يوم في حياتي.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Video) Man: I mean, I know we were hoping for good waves,
(فيديو) رجل: أعني أنني أعلم أننا كنا نأمل في الحصول على موجات جيدة،
but I don't think anybody thought that was going to happen.
ولكن لم أعتقد أن أي شخص كان يعتقد أن هذا أمر يمكن أن يحدث.
I can't stop shaking.
لا أستطيع التوقف عن الارتجاف.
I am so cold.
أشعر بالبرد القارس.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Chris Burkard: So, surf photographer, right?
كريس بوركارد: مصور ركوب أمواج، أليس كذلك؟
I don't even know if it's a real job title, to be honest.
لم أكن أدرك ما إذا كان هذا مسمى حقيقيًا لمهنتي بصراحة.
My parents definitely didn't think so
ولم يفكر والديّ في ذلك
when I told them at 19 I was quitting my job to pursue this dream career:
فعندما كان عمري 19 عامًا أخبرتهما بأنني سوف أترك وظيفتي لأتابع حلمي:
blue skies, warm tropical beaches, and a tan that lasts all year long.
السماء الزرقاء والشواطيء الاستوائية الدافئة ولون بشرة أسمر طوال السنة.
I mean, to me, this was it. Life could not get any better.
كل هذا يعني لي الكثير. ولا أتطلع إلى شيء أفضل من هذا.
Sweating it out, shooting surfers in these exotic tourist destinations.
ولذا تحملت كل الصعاب في سبيل تصوير المتزلجين في هذه الوجهات السياحية المذهلة.
But there was just this one problem.
ولكن ثمة مشكلة واحدة.
You see, the more time I spent traveling to these exotic locations,
وهو أنه كلما قضيت وقتًا أطول في السفر إلى هذه المواقع المذهلة،
the less gratifying it seemed to be.
كانت تبدو أقل روعة.
I set out seeking adventure, and what I was finding was only routine.
لقد اعتدت البحث عن المغامرة، ولكن كل ما كنت أفعله كان أمرًا اعتياديًا.
It was things like wi-fi, TV, fine dining, and a constant cellular connection
ويصبح مثل استخدام شبكة الإنترنت اللاسلكية والتليفزيون والعشاء الفاخر والاتصال الخلوي
that to me were all the trappings of places heavily touristed
وهي أمور تفقد المكان بريقه مثل الأماكن التي تعج بالسياح
in and out of the water,
سواء كان ذلك داخل الماء أو خارجه،
and it didn't take long for me to start feeling suffocated.
ولم يستغرق الأمر وقتًا طويلاً حتى بدأت أشعر بالاختناق.
I began craving wild, open spaces,
وبدأت أشتاق إلى الأماكن البرية
and so I set out to find the places others had written off
والمساحات المفتوحة، ولهذا بدأت البحث عن أماكن استبعدها الآخرون
as too cold, too remote, and too dangerous to surf,
لأنها باردة جدًا وبعيدة جدًا وخطرة جدًا لركوب الأمواج،
and that challenge intrigued me.
وكان هذا التحدي يحفزني للغاية.
I began this sort of personal crusade against the mundane,
وبدأت هذا النوع من التحدي الذاتي ضد الأمور الاعتيادية،
because if there's one thing I've realized,
وذلك لأنني أدركت أن أي مهنة أخرى
it's that any career,
مهما كانت،
even one as seemingly glamorous as surf photography,
حتى إذا كانت تبدو مثيرة جدًا مثل تصوير ركوب الأمواج،
has the danger of becoming monotonous.
يصيبها هي الأخرى خطر الرتابة.
So in my search to break up this monotony, I realized something:
وفي إبان بحثي للتغلب على هذه الرتابة، أدركت شيئًا هو أن:
There's only about a third of the Earth's oceans that are warm,
ثلث محيطات الأرض فقط دافئة،
and it's really just that thin band around the equator.
وأنها توجد في شكل حزام دقيق حول خط الاستواء.
So if I was going to find perfect waves,
وبالتالي إذا كنت أبحث عن موجات مثالية،
it was probably going to happen somewhere cold,
فمن المحتمل أن أجد ما أبحث عنه في مكان بارد جدًا،
where the seas are notoriously rough,
حيث تكون البحار متقلبة للغاية،
and that's exactly where I began to look.
وهذا ما بدأت البحث عنه بالفعل.
And it was my first trip to Iceland
ومن ثم قُمت بأول رحلة إلى أيسلندا
that I felt like I found exactly what I was looking for.
وكنت أشعر وقتها بأنني وجدت ما أتطلع إليه.
I was blown away by the natural beauty of the landscape,
وكنت مأخوذًا جدًا بالجمال الطبيعي للمناظر الخلابة،
but most importantly, I couldn't believe we were finding perfect waves
ولكن الأكثر أهمية هو أنني لم أصدق أننا عثرنا على الأمواج المثالية.
in such a remote and rugged part of the world.
في ذلك الجزء النائي والوعر من العالم.
At one point, we got to the beach
ففي أحد المراحل، وصلنا إلى الشاطيء
only to find massive chunks of ice had piled on the shoreline.
لكي نجد كتل جليد تجمعت على حافة الشاطيء.
They created this barrier between us and the surf,
وقد صنعت هذا الحاجز بيننا وبين الأمواج،
and we had to weave through this thing like a maze
وكان علينا أن نمر خلاله وكأننا نسير في متاهة
just to get out into the lineup.
فعلنا كل هذا فقط لكي نقف بالصف.
and once we got there,
وبمجرد أن وصلنا هنالك،
we were pushing aside these ice chunks trying to get into waves.
كان علينا أن ندفع كتل الجليد هذه في محاولة للوصول إلى الأمواج.
It was an incredible experience, one I'll never forget,
لقد كانت تجربة تفوق الوصف، ولن أنساها ما حييت،
because amidst those harsh conditions,
لأنه وسط كل هذه الظروف العصيبة،
I felt like I stumbled onto one of the last quiet places,
كنت أشعر بأنني أطأ أحد آخر أكثر الأماكن هدوءًا على وجه الأرض.
somewhere that I found a clarity and a connection with the world
وفي بعض الأماكن وجدت وضوحًا واتصال مع العالم
I knew I would never find on a crowded beach.
أعلم أنني لم أكن لأجده في أحد الشواطئ المزدحمة.
I was hooked. I was hooked. (Laughter)
وجدت ما كنت أبحث عنه. (ضحك)
Cold water was constantly on my mind,
فدومًا ما كانت المياه الباردة تشغل تفكيري،
and from that point on,
ومن هذه النقطة،
my career focused on these types of harsh and unforgiving environments,
أصبحت أركز في مهنتي على هذه البيئات الصعبة والنائية،
and it took me to places like Russia, Norway, Alaska, Iceland, Chile,
وأخذت أذهب إلى أماكن مثل روسيا والنرويج وألاسكا وأيسلندا وشيلي
the Faroe Islands, and a lot of places in between.
وجزر الفارو وكثير من الأماكن فيما بينها.
And one of my favorite things about these places
ولعل أحد الأمور المفضلة لي فيما يتعلق بهذه الأماكن
was simply the challenge and the creativity it took just to get there:
التحدي والإبداع المطلوبان للوصول إليها:
hours, days, weeks spent on Google Earth
كنت أقضي ساعات، بل أسابيع، على جوجل إيرث
trying to pinpoint any remote stretch of beach or reef we could actually get to.
محاولاً العثور على أي بقعة نائية على شاطيء أو شعب يمكننا الوصول إليها.
And once we got there, the vehicles were just as creative:
وبمجرد أن نصل إلى هنالك، فإن السيارات التي نستخدمها تكون مبدعة:
snowmobiles, six-wheel Soviet troop carriers,
ناقلات كتل جليد سوفيتية تسير على ست عجلات،
and a couple of super-sketchy helicopter flights.
ورحلات على متن طائرات هليوكوبتر واسعة للغاية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Helicopters really scare me, by the way.
وللعلم فإن طائرات الهيلكوبتر تخيفني للغاية.
There was this one particularly bumpy boat ride
وفي إحدى المرات أخذت زورقًا غير مجهز كوسيلة انتقال
up the coast of Vancouver Island to this kind of remote surf spot,
إلى تلك البقعة النائية لركوب الأمواج، في ساحل جزيرة فانكوفر
where we ended up watching helplessly from the water
حيث انتهى بنا المقام إلى مجرد المشاهدة من الماء عاجزين
as bears ravaged our camp site.
والدببه تدور حول معسكرنا.
They walked off with our food and bits of our tent,
ولقد أخذت طعامنا وأجزاءً من خيمتنا،
clearly letting us know that we were at the bottom of the food chain
لتتركنا ندرك أننا في آخر السلسلة الغذائية
and that this was their spot, not ours.
وأن هذا كان مكانهم، وليس مكاننا.
But to me, that trip
ولكن بالنسبة لي، فإن تلك الرحلة
was a testament to the wildness I traded for those touristy beaches.
كانت خير دليل على الطبيعة الخصبة التي استبدلتها مكان الشواطئ السياحية.
Now, it wasn't until I traveled to Norway -- (Laughter) --
ولكن لم ألحظ هذا إلا بعد أن سافرت إلى النرويج -- (ضحك) --
that I really learned to appreciate the cold.
وأنني تعلمت بالفعل أن أحترم البرد.
So this is the place
وبالتالي فإن هذا هو المكان
where some of the largest, the most violent storms in the world
الذي يوجد به بعض من أعتى العواصف وأعنفها في العالم
send huge waves smashing into the coastline.
والتي تبعث موجات ضخمة تتحطم على خط الساحل.
We were in this tiny, remote fjord, just inside the Arctic Circle.
كنا في هذا المضيق الصغير النائي داخل منطقة القطب الشمالي.
It had a greater population of sheep than people,
عدد الأغنام به أكثر من البشر،
so help if we needed it was nowhere to be found.
وبالتالي لم يمكن الحصول على أية مساعدة إذا احتجناها.
I was in the water taking pictures of surfers,
ولقد كنت في الماء ألتقط بعض الصور للمتزلجين،
and it started to snow.
وبدأ هطول الجليد.
And then the temperature began to drop.
ثم بدأت درجة الحرارة تهبط.
And I told myself, there's not a chance you're getting out of the water.
وقُلت لنفسي، لا توجد ثمة فرصة أن تخرج من الماء.
You traveled all this way, and this is exactly what you've been waiting for:
لقد قطعت كل هذا الطريق، وهذا ما كنت تنتظره بالضبط:
freezing cold conditions with perfect waves.
أحوال جوية أقرب للتجمد مع أمواج مثالية.
And although I couldn't even feel my finger to push the trigger,
وعلى الرغم من أنني لم أكن أشعر بإصبعي لكي اضغط على زر الكاميرا،
I knew I wasn't getting out.
إلا أنني كنت أعلم أنني لن أخرج.
So I just did whatever I could. I shook it off, whatever.
ولذا فعلت ما يمكنني القيام به وأنا أرتعد على أية حال.
But that was the point that I felt
وكانت هذه هي النقطة التي شعرت فيها
this wind gush through the valley and hit me,
بأن الرياح تندفع حول الوادي وترتطم بي،
and what started as this light snowfall quickly became a full-on blizzard,
وما بدأ ككرة جليد خفيفة تحول بسرعة إلى عاصفة ثلجية عنيفة،
and I started to lose perception of where I was.
وبدأت أفقد إحساسي بالمكان الذي أتواجد به.
I didn't know if I was drifting out to sea or towards shore,
ولم أكن أعلم ما إذا كنت أندفع داخل البحر أم خارجه تجاه الشاطيء،
and all I could really make out was the faint sound of seagulls
وكل ما كان يسعني القيام به هو الإصغاء للصوت الخافت لطيور النورس
and crashing waves.
والأمواج المتلاطمة.
Now, I knew this place had a reputation for sinking ships and grounding planes,
كنت أعلم أن هذا المكان يشتهر بغرق السفن والطائرات الأرضية،
and while I was out there floating, I started to get a little bit nervous.
وبينما كنت أطفو هنالك، بدأت أتوتر قليلاً.
Actually, I was totally freaking out --
في الواقع، لقد أرتعد خوفًا--
(Laughter) -- and I was borderline hypothermic,
(ضحك) -- وكنت على وشك الإغماء بسبب هبوط الحرارة،
and my friends eventually had to help me out of the water.
وفي النهاية ساعدني أصدقائي في الخروج من الماء.
And I don't know if it was delirium setting in or what,
ولا أعرف ما إذا كان هذا هذيانًا أم لا،
but they told me later
ولكنهم أخبروني بعدها
I had a smile on my face the entire time.
أن الابتسامة كانت تعلو وجهي طوال الوقت.
Now, it was this trip
والآن، لقد كانت هذه الرحلة
and probably that exact experience where I really began to feel
وربما هذه التجربة بالتحديد عندما بدأت أشعر بالفعل
like every photograph was precious,
أن كل صورة كنز ثمين،
because all of a sudden in that moment, it was something I was forced to earn.
لأنه فجأة في تلك اللحظة، كانت شيئًا اضطررت لكسبه.
And I realized, all this shivering had actually taught me something:
وأدركت أن كل هذا الارتجاف قد علمني شيئًا:
In life, there are no shortcuts to joy.
في الحياة، لا توجد طريقة مختصرة للمتعة.
Anything that is worth pursuing is going to require us to suffer
فأي شيء ذو قيمة يتطلب المعاناة
just a little bit,
حتى ولو بشكل يسير،
and that tiny bit of suffering that I did for my photography,
وأن ذلك القدر اليسير من المعاناة الذي تحملته لالتقاط صوري،
it added a value to my work that was so much more meaningful to me
قد أضاف قيمة إلى عملي وجعله ذو معنى بالنسبة لي
than just trying to fill the pages of magazines.
أكثر من مجرد محاولة ملء صفحات المجلات.
See, I gave a piece of myself in these places,
انظروا، لقد تركت جزءًا من نفسي في هذه الأماكن،
and what I walked away with
وقد حملت معي
was a sense of fulfillment I had always been searching for.
شعورًا بالإنجاز لطالما كنت أبحث عنه.
So I look back at this photograph.
ولذلك أعاود النظر إلى هذه الصورة.
It's easy to see frozen fingers and cold wetsuits
من السهل أن تشاهد أصابعًا متجمدة وملابس سباحة باردة
and even the struggle that it took just to get there,
وحتى المعاناة التي تطلبها الأمر للوصول إلى هناك،
but most of all, what I see is just joy.
ولكن أهم شيء وجدته هو المتعة بذاتها.
Thank you so much.
شكرًا جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)